Jonathon Westbrook

New York City • 917-741-4975 • jonathon.westbrook@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/jonathonwestbrook

Technical Director and Front-End Developer

15+ years of experience developing and managing high-profile projects with brands such as IBM Studios, IBM iX, Google, and Xerox. Managed a team of four developers, achieved a 300% increase in sales in 6 months, and innovated ad tech projects that cut production time by 50%. Strong in front-end development, agile, and cross-discipline teamwork.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VSA Partners • New York, New York, United States • 11/2016 - 04/2023

Associate Director Of Technology

- Solely developed and successfully launched projects: IBM Annual Report 2020, IBM Watson AI-Ops Overview, and IBM Innovation Studios, cutting resourcing costs by 50% in 3 years
- Managed a team of four developers, ensuring project success, collaboration, and technical excellence.
- Contributed to SOWs, pitch decks, and created technical briefs, showcasing a holistic understanding and improving project revenue by 25% in 2 years

Senior Developer

- Led the development of over 10 high-profile websites and design systems in 4 years, featuring brands such as IBM Studios, IBM iX, and IBM Watson Al-Ops, Xerox, and Google.
- Innovated ad tech projects for Google, driving advancements in digital advertising efficiency and cutting animation production time by 50%
- Led seminars on development, animation, design systems, and design software, displaying leadership and effective communication.

bMobilized Inc. • New York, New York, United States • 03/2012 - 03/2016

Front End Developer / Product Manager

- Achieved a 300% increase in sales in 6 months by optimizing funnels, revamping the subscription model, and revamping analytics resulting in cutting cost-per-acquisition by 75%
- Led complete redesign of homepage UI/UX, lifting conversion rates 225% and reducing steps to purchase
- Converted and designed 200+ desktop sites to mobile in 4 years, for clients such as TCS New York Marathon, The Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, and Summit Medical Group.

Council of Europe • Strasbourg Area, France • 01/2011 - 09/2011

Full Stack Developer

- Engineered and designed a custom CMS platform and architected a community portal website from the ground up.
- Developed functionality, including live chat and comments, localization, and subscription management to enhance community engagement.

Teuton Holdings • Montreal, Quebec, Canada • 03/2009 - 08/2009

Product Manager / Front End Developer

- Assumed product management of an e-commerce startup and led a complete redesign and rebuild overseeing a team of 3 developers
- Revamped the existing site design and sign-up flow, resulting in a 20% increase in sales.

La Passerelle • Montreal, Canada Area • 11/2006 - 09/2008

Full Stack Developer

- Led initiatives in information architecture and content strategy, then designed and rebuilt a complex CMS in six months, increasing user engagement by 30%.
- Developed and launched an online job application system, improving site usability by 50%

GOT Corporation • Montreal, Quebec, Canada • 10/2005 - 05/2006 Email Marketing Developer

Bell Canada • Montreal, Quebec, Canada • 02/2004 - 12/2004 Technical Consultant

McGill University • Montreal, Canada Area • 09/2000 - 05/2003 Front-end Developer and Graphic Designer

SKILLS

Adobe Experience Manager (AEM), Adobe Suite, Agile & Waterfall Methodologies, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Atomic Design, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Content Management Systems (CMS), Content Strategy, Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD), Conversion Rate Optimization (CRO), Digital Marketing, Docker, Front-end Development, Full-Stack Development, Git, Handlebars, Heroku, HTML/CSS, Information Architecture, JavaScript, Kanban, Netlify, Next.js, Node.js, Pattern Lab, PHP, PostgreSQL, Product Management, Python, Quality Assurance Standards, React.js, Responsive Web Design, REST APIs, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), SQL, Storybook, T3 Stack, Tag Management Systems, TypeScript, User Experience, Vue, Web Analytics, Web Architecture, Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG), Web Design, Web Standards

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (BA) in English Cultural Studies, World Religions, with Computer Science

McGill University • 09/2000 - 05/2003

A global leader in education, known for its fierce competitiveness and world-class training. I gained my foundational experience in web design, project management, and honed my career skills during my time at McGill University